So we just encountered our very first Bayes network and
我们刚刚学习了贝叶斯网络的基础部分
did a number of interesting calculations.
进行了一些有趣的计算
Let's now talk about Bayes Rule and look into more complex Bayes networks.
现在我们探讨贝叶斯法则 研究更加复杂的贝叶斯网络
I want to look at Bayes Rule again and
我要再次观察贝叶斯则
make an observation that is being non-trivial.
进行非平凡观察
Here is Bayes Rule, and in practice what we find is
这是贝叶斯法则 在实践中我们发现
this term here is relatively easy to compute, it's just a product.
这里的一项计算相对简单 只是乘积
Whereas this term is really hard to compute.
然而这一项计算较难
However, this term over here does not depend on what we assume for variable A.
不过这一项并不依赖于我们对变量 A 的假定值
It's just a function of B.
这只是 B 的函数
So suppose for
那么暂时假设
a moment we also care about the complementary range of not A given B.
我们也关注 P(﹁A|B) 的互补范围
For which Bayes will unfold as follows.
对此贝叶斯展开的等式如下
Then we find that the normalizer P of B is identical
我们发现正规化子 P(B)
whether we assume A on the left side or not A on the left side.
等于 A 在左侧或 ﹁A 在左侧
We also know that P of A given B plus P of not A given B must be one.
我们还知道 P(A|B) + P(﹁A|B)  等于 1
Because these are two complimentary events.
因为这是两个互补事件
It allows us to compute Bayes rule very differently by
可以让我们通过基本上忽略正规化子的情况下
basically ignoring the normalizer.
以不同方式计算贝叶斯法则
So here's how it goes.
那么这里是这样的
You compute P of A given B and
你可以计算 P’(A|B)
you're going to call this prime because it's not a real probability.
你可以把这个称作素数 因为它并不是真实的概率
It will be just P of B given A times P of A,
只是等于 P(B|A) 乘以 P(A)
which is the normalizer to the denominator of the expression over here.
即正规化子表示这个表达式的分母
We do the same thing not A.
我们对 P’(﹁A|B) 采用相同方法
So in both cases, we compute the posterior probability not
在这两个情况中 我们计算未被正规化的后验概率
normalized while omitting the normalizer B.
同时省略正规化子 B
And then we can recover the original probabilities
然后我们根据这里的值进行归一化
by normalizing based on those values over here.
恢复初始概率
So the probability of A given B, the actual probability,
所以实际概率 P(A|B)
is a normalizer eta times this not normalized form over here.
是这里正规化子 η 乘以这里未被归一化的形式
The same is true for the negation of A, over here.
同样也适用于 P(﹁A|B)
And eta is just the normalizer results by adding these two values
η 是正规化子结果
over here together as shown over here and dividing them by one.
通过这两个值相加 然后再被 1 相除
So take a look at this for a moment.
我们来观察一下它
What we've done is we deferred the calculation of the normalizer over here.
我们完成了对这里正规化子计算的推断
By computing pseudo probabilities that are non-nominalized.
通过计算未被正规化的伪概率
This made the calculation much easier.
这可以让计算更加简单
And returned everything we just folded back in the normalizer based
并且根据伪概率得到的结果 返回我们在正规化子折叠的所有内容
on the resulting pseudo probabilities and get the correct answer.
得到正确答案
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[背景音]